<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Cojorado</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000" />
<updated>2015-01-15T21:34:16-07:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/</id>
<author>
  <name>Cara Jo</name>
  <uri>http://localhost:4000/</uri>
  
</author>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's a Pirate's Favorite Race? Ragnaaaar!]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/articles/whats-a-pirates-favorite-race/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/articles/whats-a-pirates-favorite-race</id>
  <published>2015-01-14T13:45:55-07:00</published>
  <updated>2015-01-14T13:45:55-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Cara Jo</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-has-12-arms-12-legs-and-12-eyes&quot;&gt;What has 12 arms, 12 legs and 12 eyes?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-dozen-pirates&quot;&gt;A dozen pirates.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, one kick ass Ragnar Relay team! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Ragnar Relay is one of those things that you tell your mom you’re going to do and she either responds with “You’re crazy” or tries to join in. In my case it was the latter, but there are a lot of people out there who think doing a 200 mile relay over 36 hours with 11 of your friends is…crazy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I think about it, Ragnar &lt;strong&gt;IS&lt;/strong&gt; crazy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;crazy-fun&quot;&gt;Crazy fun&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the thing; Ragnar is fun, if you embrace the crazy. You have to go into it with a positive attitude and try not to let the little things get to you. Only then will you be able to experience the joy and achievement of running 200 miles as a team spread between two vans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the 2014 Colorado race, I gathered a handful of my crazy runner co-workers, and convinced a few friends to join in on this adventure from Copper Mountain to Aspen. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you even get to run, there’s somethings that need to be taken care of as a team. First - the team name. We had to come up with the best team name that represented the people on it. After many submissions to one of my many Google Forms, we settled on “Rolling Blackouts”. We landed on this because it’s a witty play on energy usage, and we have a custom beer in it’s namesake. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to mention there’s the notebooks, gear lists, food lists, van logisitics, and money.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/articles/ragnar-van.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rolling Blackouts Van&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second - getting everyone in one spot at the same time for the pre-race dinner &amp;amp; van decorating. One of our team members has a cabin in Silverthorn, which is not far from the start. He let the team take it over for the night and we all made dinner together before giggling ourselves to sleep at something like 9pm. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alarms are set for 4:45am, so that Van 1 could get on the road to the start. Someone on our team’s has their alarm tone set to the theme song from the Lego Movie, so at 4:45am we all awoke to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;“EVERYTHING IS AWESOME - EVERYTHING IS COOL WHEN YOU’RE PART OF A TEAM”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Not going to lie, it was a pretty hilarious start to the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Van 1 gets rolling bright and early and heads to the start. Van 2 however…goes back to sleep. We’re not scheduled to start for another 7 hours, and plan to take full advantage of sleeping in a bed. It did give us time to head to the grocery store to grab some last minute snacks that Van 1 needed, and to get fixings for breakfast. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We meet Van 1 at exchange 6 and start running legs 7-12. We won’t see Van 2 again for another 8 or so hours. They take advantage of the free time and go out to eat and sleep. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This piggybacking continues for the duration of the event until we finally all meetup at the finish line to cheer on runner 12 as she completes leg 36 into the finish. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;crazy-hard&quot;&gt;Crazy Hard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people think that &lt;strong&gt;running&lt;/strong&gt; Ragnar is hard. I think it’s actually the parts where you’re &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; running that’s harder. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are times you want to straight up kick people out of your van, or just want everyone to shut up so you can get 30 seconds of sleep. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re sleeping on the floor of an elementary school gym thinking to yourself “Gosh it smells like shit in here, why am I doing this?”. Or the person next to you won’t stop snoring/farting/talking. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/articles/ragnar-sleepingfloor.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sleeping on the floor with style&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The things you put into your stomach are ridiculous. I ate more random crap during the Relay then I do on a drunken Christmas treat binge. We had one member of our team bring home-made fried rice, and that was about the most sane thing I ate the whole trip. I mean I was sitting in the front of the van giving directions elbow deep into a bag of Cheetos. I didn’t even recognize myself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/articles/ragnar-friedrice.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fried Rice&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there’s the running. The race is actually quite hard, Ragnar even says that its one of their hardest races in the series. The Colorado relay is the highest in terms of elevation, and running that high in the sky is hard. Running and then stopping and then running again is harder than people think. Your leg muscles start to lock up after your 8 mile run when you’re crammed into a car chasing down your runner. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;crazy-exhausting--emotional&quot;&gt;Crazy exhausting &amp;amp; emotional&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re sleeping on the floor with your slowly deflating mattress pad because you were too tired to close the valve…whatever. Just after you finally reach that sweet spot of falling asleep, your teammates come wake you to tell you it’s time to run. Ha. Ha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the middle of the night - and we’ve been running on empty for about 20 hours, we can’t find our runner that we need to meet. Of course we’re in the middle of the mountains and have nothing that resembles cell service, so we’re just wandering around trying to find our runner, only to find out that she’s already ready and waiting at the van. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last leg of every runner’s set is always the hardest emotionally and maybe physically. There’s a moment when you’re running that last leg that you think “holy shit this is almost over…”, which is when these emotions come over you that you don’t expect. Things like “Wow - I just did this great thing with these amazing people.” or “Where the hell is the ‘one mile to go’ sign? I’ve been running for ages.” That’s when you look at your watch and you’re only .5 miles in to a 10 mile leg. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/articles/ragnar-cojo-sweat.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s literally blood, sweat, and tears out there on that last leg, maybe even some vomit. The runner before me on my last leg said “sorry I was so slow - I had to puke into a bush”. Who apologizes for that!? Half way into my last leg of 10 miles uphill, I just sat down in the middle of the course and started crying. I was dehydrated, hungry, tired, and so very hot. August sun in the middle of the day in Colorado does not make for an ‘easy run’. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My teammates were there for me though. They helped me get up, hydrated, fed and told me to “stop crying about it and just run”. Then, a mile before the finish of my last leg - I see a teammate running towards me in the rain. Oh yeah, it started pouring ice cold rain right before I finished, I’m still unsure if it was a blessing or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She ran with me to the end cheering me on, telling me I could do it, when all I wanted to do was quit. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t have done any of that without the team. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Embracing the crazy of everyone and the weekend, is what Ragnar is all about. You want to do this crazy hard thing, and these people cheer you on through the whole experience. They know you can’t do it without them, and they can’t do it without you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/articles/ragnar-kevin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kevin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/articles/whats-a-pirates-favorite-race/&quot;&gt;What's a Pirate's Favorite Race? Ragnaaaar!&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Cara Jo at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Cojorado&lt;/a&gt; on January 14, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simple Energy]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/design/simple-energy/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/design/simple-energy</id>
  <published>2015-01-13T20:30:11-07:00</published>
  <updated>2015-01-13T20:30:11-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Cara Jo</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As the Lead Designer at Simple Energy, I’ve had a chance to design some really awesome things, for a great company. I’ve been there from what feels like the beginning, starting with the company when it was only 12 people strong. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ve watched it grow into a large company of 50+ in less than two years, and with that bringing in some great talent and ideas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Design isn’t all I do at Simple Energy. I am on the engineering team, so I’m immersed deep within the produciton of our amazing products. But, that doesn’t mean I just sit in a cave all day and write code. I get to help design the office, the custom Simple Energy beer labels, the team member swag, annual holiday cards, and other goodies that make working there just more fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Below are a few of my favorite projects I’ve worked at while at Simple Energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;logo-design&quot;&gt;Logo Design&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Our old logo with Museo Sans and gradients everywhere was looking a little dates. I collaborated with a team of brand specialists to work on re-branding the company.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/design/design-04.png&quot; alt=&quot;image name&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;business-cards&quot;&gt;Business Cards&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Our brand is simple, clean, fun, and flat. When designing these business cards I wanted to bring all those elements into a 3.5” x 2” space. The leadership and sales teams all received horizontal cards, while the engineers and designers received vertical cards. But of course everyone had an option of what format they wanted! &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/design/design-03.png&quot; alt=&quot;image name&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;corporate-website&quot;&gt;Corporate Website&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;With our re-brand came a shiny new site to showcase our Engagement Platform and other products. In addition to showcasing our beautiful products, this site also reflects the great &lt;a href=&quot;http://simpleenergy.com/company/&quot;&gt;culture at Simple Energy&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/design/design-08.png&quot; alt=&quot;image name&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/design/design-09.png&quot; alt=&quot;image name&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;holiday-cards&quot;&gt;2014 Holiday Cards&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To keep up with Simple Energy’s mission of motivating people to save energy, we decided to be a little witty with this year’s holiday cards.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/design/design-02.png&quot; alt=&quot;image name&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;beer-labels&quot;&gt;Beer Labels&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Simple Energy has a brewmaster on staff, he uses his skills to create custom beer for the company. The team votes on names for each new batch, then it’s labeled and bottled for everyone to take home.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/design/design-01.png&quot; alt=&quot;image name&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;core-values-icons&quot;&gt;Core Values Icons&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;At Simple Energy we have a set of Core Values that everyone is expected to uphold. To keep those Values front and center in the culture, we were tasked with designing icons to represent them that could be used throughout the office. I collaborated with another designer to create these five. Of course Do The Hard Things and Have Fun Together are my favorite, but I’m a bit biased.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/design/design-05.png&quot; alt=&quot;image name&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;ragnar-relay-apparel&quot;&gt;Ragnar Relay Apparel&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The team members at Simple Energy are very active, and sometimes participate in crazy races together. As team captain of our company Ragnar Relay team the Rolling Blackouts, I got to design super custom race shirts. The team wore these throughout the weekend to represent the team and the company. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/design/design-06.png&quot; alt=&quot;image name&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/design/design-07.png&quot; alt=&quot;image name&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/design/simple-energy/&quot;&gt;Simple Energy&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Cara Jo at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Cojorado&lt;/a&gt; on January 13, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Girl Develop It]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/design/girl-develop-it/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/design/girl-develop-it</id>
  <published>2015-01-13T19:48:56-07:00</published>
  <updated>2015-01-13T19:48:56-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Cara Jo</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Girl Develop It is a non-profit that empowers women to learn software development. During the 3 years I’ve been with GDI I’ve had some time to design assets for the whole organization, of over 198 women leaders, to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;business-cards&quot;&gt;Business Cards&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;These are customized down to the chapter level.  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/design/design-15.png&quot; alt=&quot;image name&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;holiday-cards&quot;&gt;Holiday Cards&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As a thank you to our sponsors and volunteers, chapters send out hand written Holiday Cards every year.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/design/design-13.png&quot; alt=&quot;image name&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;invitation&quot;&gt;Invitation&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Chapters have launch parties and other large events that need more legit looking invitaions than MeetUp can provide.   &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/design/design-14.png&quot; alt=&quot;image name&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;chapter-map&quot;&gt;Chapter Map&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Another resource for chapters is having an accurate representation of the impact Girl Develop It is having across the country. This is used in posters, advertising, presentations and on the website.   &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/design/design-17.png&quot; alt=&quot;image name&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;stickers&quot;&gt;Stickers&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Often times chapters don’t have the resources to create their own stickers for their chapters or events. Templates are provided for them to allow them to do this.    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/design/design-16.png&quot; alt=&quot;image name&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/design/girl-develop-it/&quot;&gt;Girl Develop It&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Cara Jo at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Cojorado&lt;/a&gt; on January 13, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Freelance]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/design/freelance/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/design/freelance</id>
  <published>2015-01-13T18:06:37-07:00</published>
  <updated>2015-01-13T18:06:37-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Cara Jo</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/design/freelance/&quot;&gt;Freelance&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Cara Jo at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Cojorado&lt;/a&gt; on January 13, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Involved With Girl Develop It in 2015]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/articles/get-involved-with-girl-develop-it-in-2015/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/articles/get-involved-with-girl-develop-it-in-2015</id>
  <published>2015-01-13T14:54:01-07:00</published>
  <updated>2015-01-13T14:54:01-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Cara Jo</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Girl Develop It is now in over &lt;a href=&quot;http://girldevelopit.com/chapters&quot;&gt;45 cities across the country&lt;/a&gt;. It’s pretty simple to see why; we offer affordable opportunities for women to learn software development. In nearly 5 years Girl Develop It has grown to nearly 30,000 members across the country and empowers over 1,000 women a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/articles/chapter-locations.png&quot; alt=&quot;Chapter Locations&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is Girl Develop It so important? Women make up half of the U.S. workforce, but hold just 25% of the jobs in technical or computing fields. I personally don’t like those numbers, and I’m not alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why I started a local chapter here in Boulder, Colorado. I wanted to help diversify this heavily white male scene. Seriously it’s like every developer here is a white male, it’s actually impressive the lack of diversity. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I landed in Boulder in early 2013 the first thing I did was explore the idea of starting a Girl Develop It out here. I had helped start one in Detroit and saw it’s success there and wanted to spread that across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;local-success&quot;&gt;Local Success&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the one year and a half that Girl Develop It Boulder has been around we’ve achieved a lot. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We have grown to 880 members&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/articles/boulder-party.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Boulder 1 Year Birthday&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Offered over 25 different &lt;em&gt;types&lt;/em&gt; of classes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/articles/boulder-python.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Python&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’ve built up a community through our free social events&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/articles/code-cocktails.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Code &amp;amp; Cocktails&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boulder wasn’t enough - so we expanded to Denver and Fort Collins too&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/articles/denver-class.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Denver&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-future&quot;&gt;The future&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the group grows, so do the needs of its members. We want to make sure that everyone has access to the tools they need to feel empowered. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;new-classes&quot;&gt;New classes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our classes are designed to break down what can seem like a daunting topic - to it’s fundamentals. Classes are typically 8 hours and are taught over a weekend. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start we want to offer some new classes like Python, Ruby, Android, iOs, Java, UX, and more. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;new-workshops&quot;&gt;New Workshops&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Workshops are a great opportunity for our members to get their hands dirty with a new topic without committing to a whole class. These topics are usually taught in 2-3 hours on a weekday. We want to offer a huge (seriously huge) range of new workshops this year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to start we’re going to offer workshops like Sketch 3, Photoshop, Agile/Scrum, Behavioral Science, WordPress, FTP &amp;amp; GitHub Pages, Bootstrap, LESS, SASS, Sublime, Command Line, Docker and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;women-in-tech-panel-series&quot;&gt;Women in Tech panel series&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re putting together a 6 week Women in Tech panel series for the spring. We will be bringing together some of the most amazing Women in the Boulder/Denver tech scene to inspire our members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;more-community-events&quot;&gt;More community events&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy Hour, Code &amp;amp; Coffee, Hack nights, and other social events really help our members connect with one another and create lasting relationships. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;teacher-training&quot;&gt;Teacher Training&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming this year! GDI will offer teacher training so you get the skills you need to be a successful instructor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-need-you&quot;&gt;We Need You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to be a woman to help. You don’t have to be a rockstar developer. You don’t have to jump right in. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;there-are-many-ways-to-help&quot;&gt;There are many ways to help&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;instruct&quot;&gt;Instruct&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Co-Teach or run solo, for a class and/or workshop!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;teacher-assist&quot;&gt;Teacher Assist&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Answer student questions and provide added insight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;develop-curriculum&quot;&gt;Develop Curriculum&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have something you want to teach, there’s probably people who want to learn it.
Review/enhance existing curriculum or create new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;organizational-needs&quot;&gt;Organizational Needs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Help out with marketing, social media, class scheduling, work with sponsors, answer student questions, &amp;amp; more&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;provide-space&quot;&gt;Provide Space&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Show off your awesome workspace by hosting a workshop, happy hour, or class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;donate-time&quot;&gt;Donate Time&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a crew of developers? Have your team TA or even teach a class for GDI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;donate-resources&quot;&gt;Donate Resources&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food, Drinks, Supplies, &amp;amp; swag all help make the learning experience better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;other-ideas&quot;&gt;Other Ideas?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We always open to ideas for classes, programming and overall improvements for this chapter. Please feel free to speak to one of our chapter leaders, or email us at boulder@girldevelopit.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fill out the volunteer interest survey at &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdiboulder.com/support&quot;&gt;gdiboulder.com/support&lt;/a&gt; to get started with Girl Develop It Boulder. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If donating money is more your thing, you can &lt;a href=&quot;http://girldevelopit.com/donate&quot;&gt;donate to a chapter&lt;/a&gt; or the global organization.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/articles/get-involved-with-girl-develop-it-in-2015/&quot;&gt;Get Involved With Girl Develop It in 2015&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Cara Jo at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Cojorado&lt;/a&gt; on January 13, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pattern: Norwegian Star Hat]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/knitting/pattern-norwegian-star-hat/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/knitting/pattern-norwegian-star-hat</id>
  <published>2014-12-24T12:57:57-07:00</published>
  <updated>2014-12-24T12:57:57-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Cara Jo</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ravelry.com/badges/redirect?p=basic-norwegian-star-hat&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://api.ravelry.com/badges/projects?p=basic-norwegian-star-hat&amp;amp;t=.gif&quot; style=&quot;border: none;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/knitting/norwegian-white1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This pattern is available for download on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ravelry.com/patterns/library/basic-norwegian-star-hat&quot;&gt;Ravelry.com&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;materials&quot;&gt;Materials:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worsted weight (4) yarn. 1 skein of each color. You will not use the entire skein of any color.
Size 6 circular needles size 6 double pointed needles&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gauge&quot;&gt;Gauge:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 inches = 20 stitches and 27 rows&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;size&quot;&gt;Size:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hat will fit heads up to 58cm in diameter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the size 6 needles, loosely cast on (112) stitches.
&lt;em&gt;Note: Pattern is worked over 16sts so if you need a smaller or larger hat make sure you cast on enough stitches to accommodate for a 16st pattern repeat.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knit in K2, P2 ribbing for desired length (an inch or two for a beanie).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After cuff is desired length begin knitting in stockinette stitch (knit every round). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/knitting/norwegian-grid.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continue until the end of the pattern. Pattern is worked over 16 sts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knit 1 row in main color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;begin-decreases&quot;&gt;Begin Decreases:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: Switch to the double pointed needles when you don’t have enough stitches for the circular needles.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* K14, K2tog* Repeat around. Knit 1 round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*K13, K2tog* Repeat around. Knit 1 round&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*K12, K2tog* Repeat around. Knit 1 round&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*K11, K2tog* Repeat around. Knit 1 round&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*K10, K2tog* Repeat around. Knit 1 round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*K9, K2tog* Repeat around. Knit 1 round.	&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*K8, K2tog* Repeat around. Knit 1 round.	&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*K7, K2tog* Repeat around. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*K6, K2tog* Repeat around. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*K5, K2tog* Repeat around. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*K4, k2tog*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*K3, k2tog*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*K2tog* Repeat around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cut yarn, leaving at least 12 inches. Thread onto a needle, and weave the yarn through the remaining stitches. Weave through the stitches twice, if you choose. Tighten the top of the hat and weave in the ends. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ravelry.com/badges/redirect?p=basic-norwegian-star-hat&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://api.ravelry.com/badges/projects?p=basic-norwegian-star-hat&amp;amp;t=.gif&quot; style=&quot;border: none;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/knitting/norwegian-gray1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/knitting/pattern-norwegian-star-hat/&quot;&gt;Pattern: Norwegian Star Hat&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Cara Jo at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Cojorado&lt;/a&gt; on December 24, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[2014 a Year in Photos]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/photography/2014-a-year-in-photos/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/photography/2014-a-year-in-photos</id>
  <published>2014-12-24T12:10:55-07:00</published>
  <updated>2014-12-24T12:10:55-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Cara Jo</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;2014 was a great year for taking photographs. I went on a lot of adventures to Utah and other areas in Colorado I had never been before. My obsession with Moab started in March and is still going strong. Camping in the middle of the mountains also provided great inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In November I made the big switch to Nikon and purchased the D610 full frame camera. As pathetic as it is, this is the same time that I discovered HDR images. I tread lightly when creating HDR images because that edge glow can get a little crazy. With the help of Keith’s awesome collection of photography supplies I also discovered how amazing it can be to take panorama photos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/carajo/15795432897/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/photography/2014-arch-daylight.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Delicate Arch&quot; title=&quot;Delicate Arch&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/carajo/13934189692/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/photography/2014-arch-april.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Delicate Arch&quot; title=&quot;Delicate Arch&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/carajo/14297900668/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/photography/2014-hayden-creek.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hayden Creek&quot; title=&quot;Hayden Creek&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/carajo/15172119186/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/photography/2014-maroon-bells.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Maroon Bells&quot; title=&quot;Maroon Bells&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/carajo/15172115126/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/photography/2014-aspen.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Aspen&quot; title=&quot;Aspen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/carajo/15526928434/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/photography/2014-castle-valley.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Castle Valley&quot; title=&quot;Castle Valley&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/carajo/15955390596/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/photography/2014-deadhorse-point.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Deadhorse Point&quot; title=&quot;Deadhorse Point&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/carajo/15288682433/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/photography/2014-denver-pano.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Denver&quot; title=&quot;Downtown Denver&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/carajo/15795430827/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/photography/2014-denver-county.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Denver County Building&quot; title=&quot;Denver County Building&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/carajo/15504103843/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/photography/2014-boulder-flatirons.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Boulder Flatirons&quot; title=&quot;Boulder Flatirons&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/photography/2014-a-year-in-photos/&quot;&gt;2014 a Year in Photos&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Cara Jo at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Cojorado&lt;/a&gt; on December 24, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pattern: Brioche Weather Scarf]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/knitting/pattern-brioche-weather-scarf/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/knitting/pattern-brioche-weather-scarf</id>
  <published>2014-12-23T16:36:10-07:00</published>
  <updated>2014-12-23T16:36:10-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Cara Jo</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently, I was in New York attending the 2014 Girl Develop It Leadership Summit. One of the chapter leaders that I was sitting next to was knitting a small project and we started talking about all the other awesome projects she was working on. She had briefly mentioned that she was also working on a ‘weather scarf’ and initially I thought “what else would you use a scarf in, besides weather?”. She went on to explain that each row was it’s own color that was based on the average temperature for that day. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought more about it and decided that would be a fun project to do for 2015. I generally fail at knitting throughout the year, and binge knit in the winter months. Knitting is a nice stress release for me and allows me time to wind down at the end of the day. It also keeps my hands occupied so I don’t chew on them so much. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;many-questions&quot;&gt;Many Questions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a few things I needed to get ready before I jumped into knitting 365 rows of colors. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What yarn was I going to use?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Would it have enough colors for me? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How many degrees would each color represent? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What degrees will be in each color? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How many yards of yarn will I need? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where will I get the weather data from? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What pattern will I use? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What size needles? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;yarn&quot;&gt;Yarn&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I opted to go with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yarnspirations.com/vickie-howell-sheep-ish.html&quot;&gt;Bernat’s line of yarn called Sheep(ish)&lt;/a&gt; which you can get at Jo-Ann Fabrics. I’ve used it before, and it is nice and soft against the skin. I’m a strange cat and only like single ply yarn, it just creates such clean stitches. It’s also relatively inexpensive, at $3.99 a skein you can’t go wrong! It also comes in a large variety of colors, so I figured they would have enough colors for my temperature gauge. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The colors I went with, in order from ‘coldest’ to ‘hottest’:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Raspberry(ish)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plum(ish)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Navy(ish)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Teal(ish)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turquoise(ish)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chartreuse(ish)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yellow(ish)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coral(ish)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Orange(ish) &lt;em&gt;Updated from Pumpkin(ish)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Red(ish)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/knitting/brioche-swatch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Swatch&quot; title=&quot;Color Swatch&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went with 10 colors because I had originally wanted to go from 0-100 degrees with each color representing 10 degrees. I changed how many degrees each color represented, but still stuck with the 10 colors. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-issue-about-the-weather&quot;&gt;The issue about the weather&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially I thought, I could just wing it, and figure out the weather on the fly. The more I thought about that, the more I decided that was a terrible idea. I wouldn’t know how much yarn to buy, and what colors, and how many colors. I set out in search of yearly weather data to help a girl out. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wunderground is my favorite weather source, for many reasons. My new favorite reason is the fact that they have an impressive &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wunderground.com/history/airport/KBDU/2014/1/1/MonthlyHistory.html#observations_details&quot;&gt;archive of weather data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find the average temperature for each day I took the high and the low and found the average of those temperatures. I then popped the values into a spreadsheet and went to town. I filled a spreadsheet with all 365 days of 2013’s weather data to set a baseline for future years. I picked 2013 because it has a full year’s worth of data, instead of 2014 which is still in progress. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/knitting/brioche-fullspread.png&quot; alt=&quot;Brioche Spreadsheet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Keith’s spreadsheet wizardry, we wrote a pretty fantastic sheet to do all these calculations for us. First, we find the average high for the year, then the low. Then we take that number and divide it by 9. Why 9? Because it’s the number of colors minus 1… After we’ve divided the averages by 9 we have what we like to call the DEGREES OF SEPARATION. This is how many degrees represent each color. In this example our degress of separation is 9, so each color represents 9 degrees of change. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/knitting/brioche-degsep.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Math is hard, that is why Keith does it for me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we have how many degrees represent each color - we can then assign color values to each cell in the spreadsheet that gives us a good representation of what the scarf will look like. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/knitting/brioche-allmonths.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-pattern&quot;&gt;The pattern&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past I’ve struggled with making scarves because I find them boring and long. But then one day, I discovered the Brioche stitch, and my life has never been the same. The Brioche stitch is a magical stitch that makes all ribbing fluffy, enjoyable, and fast! I hate ribbing - but love how it’s reversible. A lot of people are intimidated by the Brioche stitch because it has an abundance of annoying acronyms. Let me tell you friends, it’s nothing but pure speed knitting satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;heres-the-super-easy-pattern&quot;&gt;Here’s the super easy pattern:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE 1/1/2015: I have updated the edging to be more consistent and not bunch up on the sides.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CO 34 stitches with size 7 needles&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wyf&lt;/strong&gt;: With yarn held in front as if to purl&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set up Row:&lt;/strong&gt; K2, *(wyf) slip 1, YO, K1; repeat from * to last two stitches, K1, S1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pattern Row :&lt;/strong&gt; K2 *(wyf) slip 1, K2TOG; repeat from * to last two stitches K1, S1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Repeat Pattern Row twice for each day, this will create what appears as one row. Since the Brioche stitch is a special fluffy flower, two rows equal what appears to be one wide row. By doing two rows each day, all the yarn ends will stay on the same side of the scarf and you won’t run into that problem of having the yarn you need on the other side of the row. The two stitches on either side of the pattern are to create a clean edge up the scarf, optional if you’re not into that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;repeat&quot;&gt;Repeat&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make this work for 2015, I had to do a few things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set up the base high and low. Remember above when I mentioned that the average high and low were calculated throughout the year? Well that’s cool - except if I’m giving the spreadsheet new data every day. Those numbers are going to change on the daily, and mess up my degrees of separation, which will in turn mess up the colors that represent each temperature range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/knitting/brioche-basedata.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make sure that didn’t happen, I used the data from 2014 to set a base, and then took the ability for the spreadsheet to calculate away. I put in static numbers for the high and the low, which gave me 9 degrees of separation. Now when I enter new data every day in 2015, things won’t get recalculated and I won’t need to frog this scarf! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;you-can-do-it-too&quot;&gt;You can do it too!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve made the spreadsheet &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1pjsKu63y7HSVjkdF7K62ibfLJBV95QZR4Mbh4eoGtWc/edit?usp=sharing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;publicly available&lt;/a&gt; for this pattern, with all the work already done for you! All you need to do is enter in the highs and the lows for each day and it will calculate everything for you. Questions? Comment below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: anywhere you see a light blue cell is a cell you can edit. Well you can edit any cell you want - but these special blue cells are the ones that are used for calulations&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have provided two tabs for you to get started. Tab one, is the previous year’s data. This will help you set up a baseline temperature to calculate the degrees of separation, as well as calculate the yardage you’ll need of each color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The colors are conditional statements that you can change to match your color scheme.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/knitting/brioche-conditional.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get a proper yardage calculation enter in the yardage per skein. If you are going to use a different pattern you should knit at one row in the pattern and then measure how many inches that row uses of yarn. This number is what calculates the yards used. Inches per row divided by 36 = yards of yarn you need to buy.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/knitting/brioche-yardage.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also provided you with some links to sample data from Wunderground. This is currently set to my location here in Boulder, CO. Feel free to update those to match your zipcode! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t forget to copy this to your Google Drive by going to &lt;em&gt;File &amp;gt; Make a Copy&lt;/em&gt;. This way you can edit it and you won’t lose any changes.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/knitting/brioche-makecopy.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fun fact, my scarf will contain 24,820 stitches and enough yarn to span over 7 football fields! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers to 2015! &lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/knitting/pattern-brioche-weather-scarf/&quot;&gt;Pattern: Brioche Weather Scarf&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Cara Jo at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Cojorado&lt;/a&gt; on December 23, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>
